<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Jonathan Goldfarb</title><link>https://jgoldfar.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Jonathan Goldfarb</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2017 11:33:47 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jgoldfar.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Working With Me - A Manual For Transparent Collaboration</title><link>https://jgoldfar.github.io/blog/2021/05/21/working-with-me/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 May 2021 09:33:47 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jgoldfar.github.io/blog/2021/05/21/working-with-me/</guid><description>Working With Jonathan Goldfarb Since I have felt a dedication to authenticity and transparency my entire professional career, I am a bit embarrassed that I didn&amp;rsquo;t come up with the concept of a &amp;ldquo;user manual&amp;rdquo; for myself. Who hasn&amp;rsquo;t avoided going to an office-mate or boss because they weren&amp;rsquo;t sure how productive the conversation would be? Those kinds of missed opportunities can so easily be avoided with open communication in an organization.</description></item><item><title>FOMO &amp; FOBO</title><link>https://jgoldfar.github.io/glossary/fomo-and-fobo/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 11:33:47 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jgoldfar.github.io/glossary/fomo-and-fobo/</guid><description>The terms &amp;ldquo;FOMO&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;FOBO&amp;rdquo; are common parlance in some groups - not everyone is familiar with both terms, and how some individuals in roles such as sales use FOMO or FOBO to try to influence prospective buyers. Both are fear-based factors, fundamentally - research in economics seems to suggest that some significant percentage of buyer choice is actually emotional rather than rational, so companies wanting to maximize conversion are bound to use powerful emotions like fear to try to land a sale.</description></item><item><title>Simple Python Hash Table</title><link>https://jgoldfar.github.io/blog/2021/04/22/python-hashtable/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Apr 2021 09:00:47 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jgoldfar.github.io/blog/2021/04/22/python-hashtable/</guid><description>&lt;p>The &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hash_table">hash table&lt;/a> or hash map is one of the fundamental data structures in computing.
It is an abstraction that allows a programming language user to think about
their problem at a level that is closer to the specifications developed for
business processes, instead of considering how the associated data is stored.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What Is This? Some Context</title><link>https://jgoldfar.github.io/blog/2021/03/27/about/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Mar 2021 09:00:47 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jgoldfar.github.io/blog/2021/03/27/about/</guid><description>This section of my site is a web log, a collection of writings and other combinations of images, text, and media expressed in visual form. I subscribe to the notion that having good ideas is a matter of having lots of ideas and selecting the best among them - ideas are not worth much on their own, but in my experience, there is value in adapting the correct convex combination to challenging problems.</description></item><item><title>Why Noether Rudin?</title><link>https://jgoldfar.github.io/blog/2020/06/22/why-noether-rudin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2020 10:26:50 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jgoldfar.github.io/blog/2020/06/22/why-noether-rudin/</guid><description>&lt;p>Originally published on blog.noetherrudin.com, then on blog.getdolr.com, this piece summarized my support for an effort to get more money for people&amp;rsquo;s student loans.
I still love developing, sharing, and applying knowledge in service of good causes.
If you would like to find out more, &lt;a href="https://jgoldfar.github.io/contact">contact me!&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://jgoldfar.github.io/glossary/glossary/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jgoldfar.github.io/glossary/glossary/</guid><description>A glossary is a listing of definitions, concepts, jargon, and other terms. It serves as a mapping between high-order concepts and their simpler counterparts.
Some of the hardest things to get right - both in mind of the student and the teacher - are the correct definitions and concepts. Once you have those, oftentimes statements of fact - like theorems - become easier to form and comprehend. Then, paraphrasing an idea from mathematics, once we have statements of fact, we find the reasoning easily enough.</description></item><item><title>Collaboration: Understand, Develop, and Empower</title><link>https://jgoldfar.github.io/about/collaboration/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jgoldfar.github.io/about/collaboration/</guid><description>As a collaborator, I believe that language and practice must go hand in hand when developing a work product; furthermore, my experience has suggested that delivering anything valuable requires more opinions, more eyes, and more perspectives, not fewer. While developing the wide variety of skills necessary to be successful in the day-to-day business of being productive as a technical contributor, I have observed that a mindset of perpetual learning helps me to engage as a member of cross-functional teams of any size.</description></item><item><title>Curriculum Vitae &amp; Contact Form</title><link>https://jgoldfar.github.io/contact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jgoldfar.github.io/contact/</guid><description>I am an experienced technical contributor and generalist with demonstrated ability to negotiate requirements, establish specifications, and deliver value on greenfield and legacy applications. I am passionate about managing risk, engaging with complex systems and the teams managing them, and collaboratively building quality products. I am interested in growing as a technologist, communicator, and creator; I love understanding new problems and domains, and conversing with individuals with perspectives different from my own.</description></item><item><title>Innovation: Assess, Experiment, and Iterate</title><link>https://jgoldfar.github.io/about/innovation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jgoldfar.github.io/about/innovation/</guid><description>“People think focus means saying yes to the thing you&amp;rsquo;ve got to focus on. But that&amp;rsquo;s not what it means at all. It means saying no to the hundred other good ideas that there are. You have to pick carefully. I&amp;rsquo;m actually as proud of the things we haven&amp;rsquo;t done as the things I have done. Innovation is saying no to 1,000 things.” &amp;ndash; Steve Jobs
As Jobs observes, there is more to innovation than just collaboration: true innovation, perhaps in the form of a Pareto improvement over the status quo, also requires deliberate focus on executing a positive vision.</description></item><item><title>Services: Freelance, Contract, etc.</title><link>https://jgoldfar.github.io/about/services/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jgoldfar.github.io/about/services/</guid><description>“Difficulties strengthen the mind, as labor does the body.” ― Lucius Annaeus Seneca
In the projects I have collaborated on, I tackled poorly defined challenges and created a body of work for understanding their solutions together with skilled colleagues. We delivered products that delighted stakeholders for projects at small and large scales, whether measured in terms of person-year investment or LoC. I found joy in being able to talk with creative people and domain experts about their problems, and contributing to their growth where I can provide value.</description></item></channel></rss>