<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Jonathan Goldfarb</title><link>https://jgoldfar.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Jonathan Goldfarb</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2017 11:33:47 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jgoldfar.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Simple Python Hash Table</title><link>https://jgoldfar.github.io/vault/python-hashtable/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Apr 2021 09:00:47 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jgoldfar.github.io/vault/python-hashtable/</guid><description>&lt;p>The &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hash_table">hash table&lt;/a> or hash map is one of the fundamental data structures in computing.
It is an abstraction that allows a programming language user to think about
their problem at a level that is closer to the specifications developed for
business processes, instead of considering how the associated data is stored.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Why Noether Rudin?</title><link>https://jgoldfar.github.io/vault/why-noether-rudin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2020 10:26:50 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jgoldfar.github.io/vault/why-noether-rudin/</guid><description>&lt;p>Originally published on blog.noetherrudin.com, then on blog.getdolr.com, this piece summarized my support for an effort to get more money for people&amp;rsquo;s student loans.
I still love developing, sharing, and applying knowledge in service of good causes.
If you would like to find out more, &lt;a href="https://jgoldfar.github.io/contact">contact me!&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://jgoldfar.github.io/glossary/glossary/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jgoldfar.github.io/glossary/glossary/</guid><description>A glossary is a listing of definitions, concepts, jargon, and other terms. It serves as a mapping between high-order concepts and their simpler counterparts.
In my years of experience in education, I have found that one of the hardest things to get right - both in mind of the student and the teacher - is the correct definitions and concepts. Once you have those, oftentimes statements of fact - like theorems - become easier to form and comprehend.</description></item><item><title>Collaboration: Understand, Develop, and Empower</title><link>https://jgoldfar.github.io/about/collaboration/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jgoldfar.github.io/about/collaboration/</guid><description>As a collaborator, I believe that language and practice must go hand in hand when developing a work product; furthermore, my experience has suggested that delivering anything valuable requires more opinions, more eyes, and more perspectives, not fewer. While developing the wide variety of skills necessary to be successful in the day-to-day business of being productive as a technical contributor, I have observed that a mindset of perpetual learning helps me to engage as a member of cross-functional teams of any size.</description></item><item><title>Curriculum Vitae &amp; Contact Form</title><link>https://jgoldfar.github.io/contact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jgoldfar.github.io/contact/</guid><description>I am an experienced technical contributor and generalist with demonstrated ability to negotiate requirements, establish specifications, and deliver value on greenfield and legacy applications. I am passionate about managing risk, engaging with complex systems, and building quality products. I am interested in growing as a technologist, communicator, and creator; I love understanding new problems and domains, and conversing with individuals with perspectives different from my own. Don&amp;rsquo;t hesitate to reach out if you want to know more, or have anything to share!</description></item><item><title>Innovation: Assess, Experiment, and Iterate</title><link>https://jgoldfar.github.io/about/innovation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jgoldfar.github.io/about/innovation/</guid><description>“People think focus means saying yes to the thing you&amp;rsquo;ve got to focus on. But that&amp;rsquo;s not what it means at all. It means saying no to the hundred other good ideas that there are. You have to pick carefully. I&amp;rsquo;m actually as proud of the things we haven&amp;rsquo;t done as the things I have done. Innovation is saying no to 1,000 things.” &amp;ndash; Steve Jobs
As Jobs observes, there is more to innovation than just collaboration: true innovation, perhaps in the form of a Pareto improvement over the status quo, also requires deliberate focus on executing a positive vision.</description></item></channel></rss>