<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Jonathan Goldfarb</title><link>https://jgoldfar.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Jonathan Goldfarb</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2017 11:33:47 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jgoldfar.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Collaboration: Understand, Develop, and Empower</title><link>https://jgoldfar.github.io/about/collaboration/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jgoldfar.github.io/about/collaboration/</guid><description>As a collaborator, I believe that language and practice must go hand in hand when developing a work product; furthermore, my experience has suggested that delivering anything valuable requires more opinions, more eyes, and more perspectives, not fewer. While developing the wide variety of skills necessary to be successful in the day-to-day business of being productive as a technical contributor, I have observed that a mindset of perpetual learning helps me to engage as a member of cross-functional teams of any size.</description></item><item><title>Curriculum Vitae &amp; Contact Form</title><link>https://jgoldfar.github.io/contact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jgoldfar.github.io/contact/</guid><description>I am an experienced technical consultant with demonstrated ability to gather requirements, develop specifications, and implement applications in the Defense, Finance, Education, and Medical Information industries. I am passionate about managing risk, engaging with complex systems, and building quality products. I am interested in growing as a technologist, consultant, and communicator; I have never met a problem or domain I don&amp;rsquo;t want to understand more.
This is my contact page and an abbreviated listing of my experience - my most recent resume information is available on LinkedIn or here (PDF).</description></item><item><title>Innovation: Assess, Experiment, and Iterate</title><link>https://jgoldfar.github.io/about/innovation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jgoldfar.github.io/about/innovation/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>