<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>About on Jonathan Goldfarb</title><link>https://jgoldfar.github.io/about/</link><description>Recent content in About on Jonathan Goldfarb</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://jgoldfar.github.io/about/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Collaborative Discovery</title><link>https://jgoldfar.github.io/about/collaboration/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jgoldfar.github.io/about/collaboration/</guid><description>I define collaboration as inclusive, results-driven partnerships built around common goals; in my work, I prioritize connection and communication to unlock the insights necessary to increase efficiency and deliver operational benefits. In a rapidly changing environment, the only way to successfully adapt is to accept more opinions, more perspectives, and finally more action - I take a people-first approach to understanding your organization&amp;rsquo;s vision and goals.
For many projects, technology is actually a small but critical component in the processes producing good outcomes; in my experience, a focus on actively listening to stakeholders and domain experts provides a basis for strategic discussions around adapting to changing conditions and progressing towards long-term goals.</description></item><item><title>Contract Services: Working with Me</title><link>https://jgoldfar.github.io/about/services/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jgoldfar.github.io/about/services/</guid><description>I offer professional services in all areas of digital transformation for teams tasked with delivering effectively on business challenges; if you know your outcomes aren&amp;rsquo;t meeting expectations, we can drive their improvement.
Collaborative Discovery. By assessing the goals and the space, developing an understanding of your mission and values, and aligning with your existing strategy, we identify actionable options for pushing your goals forward.
Innovative Design and Implementation. From identifying gaps in compliance to coordinating and accelerating project delivery to optimizing your critical processes, I bring my expertise to your challenges and deliver on defined business objectives.</description></item><item><title>Innovative Design and Implementation</title><link>https://jgoldfar.github.io/about/innovation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jgoldfar.github.io/about/innovation/</guid><description>“People think focus means saying yes to the thing you&amp;rsquo;ve got to focus on. But that&amp;rsquo;s not what it means at all. It means saying no to the hundred other good ideas that there are. You have to pick carefully. I&amp;rsquo;m actually as proud of the things we haven&amp;rsquo;t done as the things I have done. Innovation is saying no to 1,000 things.” &amp;ndash; Steve Jobs
As Jobs observes, there is more to innovation than just collaboration: as much as inclusion of diverse ideas and the facilitation of a vibrant discussion creates a strong starting point for growth, innovation also requires a deliberate focus on executing a positive vision, and evolving in response to changing conditions.</description></item><item><title>Privacy Policy</title><link>https://jgoldfar.github.io/about/privacy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jgoldfar.github.io/about/privacy/</guid><description>PRIVACY NOTICE
Last updated September 17, 2021
Thank you for choosing to be part of our community at Desert Frog Solutions, LLC. ("Company," "we," "us," or "our"). We are committed to protecting your personal information and your right to privacy. If you have any questions or concerns about this privacy notice or our practices with regard to your personal information, please contact us at jgoldfar@gmail.com.
This privacy notice describes how we might use your information if you:Visit our website at https://jgoldfar.</description></item></channel></rss>