<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>About on Jonathan Goldfarb</title><link>https://jgoldfar.github.io/about/</link><description>Recent content in About on Jonathan Goldfarb</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://jgoldfar.github.io/about/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Collaboration: Understand, Develop, and Empower</title><link>https://jgoldfar.github.io/about/collaboration/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jgoldfar.github.io/about/collaboration/</guid><description>As a collaborator, I believe that language and practice must go hand in hand when developing a work product; furthermore, my experience has suggested that delivering anything valuable requires more opinions, more eyes, and more perspectives, not fewer. While developing the wide variety of skills necessary to be successful in the day-to-day business of being productive as a technical contributor, I have observed that a mindset of perpetual learning helps me to engage as a member of cross-functional teams of any size.</description></item><item><title>Innovation: Assess, Experiment, and Iterate</title><link>https://jgoldfar.github.io/about/innovation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jgoldfar.github.io/about/innovation/</guid><description>“People think focus means saying yes to the thing you&amp;rsquo;ve got to focus on. But that&amp;rsquo;s not what it means at all. It means saying no to the hundred other good ideas that there are. You have to pick carefully. I&amp;rsquo;m actually as proud of the things we haven&amp;rsquo;t done as the things I have done. Innovation is saying no to 1,000 things.” &amp;ndash; Steve Jobs
As Jobs observes, there is more to innovation than just collaboration: true innovation, perhaps in the form of a Pareto improvement over the status quo, also requires deliberate focus on executing a positive vision.</description></item></channel></rss>