<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>web log on Jonathan Goldfarb</title><link>https://jgoldfar.github.io/blog/</link><description>Recent content in web log on Jonathan Goldfarb</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2017 11:33:47 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jgoldfar.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How To Make Sense of the NodeJS Event Loop</title><link>https://jgoldfar.github.io/blog/2021/06/12/how-to-make-sense-of-nodejs-event-loop/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2021 09:00:47 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jgoldfar.github.io/blog/2021/06/12/how-to-make-sense-of-nodejs-event-loop/</guid><description>When you&amp;rsquo;re writing JavaScript code for NodeJS, you don&amp;rsquo;t often need to think about how your code will be executed. You may be thinking about the models you are working with, how data moves through your application, or what guarantees you need to be able to provide to meet your acceptance criteria - or you may have another framework in mind.
One of the great things about JavaScript on the Node runtime as a developer is that you get to write code at a high level and have your code execute efficiently on hardware.</description></item><item><title>Python + Flask CRUD Application Scaffold</title><link>https://jgoldfar.github.io/blog/2021/06/05/python-flask-crud-application/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jun 2021 09:00:47 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jgoldfar.github.io/blog/2021/06/05/python-flask-crud-application/</guid><description>I have found it useful to prepare boilerplate code for spinning up things like a new application; in this article, I&amp;rsquo;ll share some code for prototyping an application that can create, retrieve, update, and delete records from a database using Flask.
For developers with experience with Django, Flask is familiar but with a smaller footprint, and leaves more up to the application architect when it comes to implementation details like form validation and data persistence.</description></item><item><title>All Finite Things Reveal Infinitude</title><link>https://jgoldfar.github.io/blog/2021/05/31/finite-things-reveal-infinitude/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 May 2021 10:26:50 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jgoldfar.github.io/blog/2021/05/31/finite-things-reveal-infinitude/</guid><description>All finite things reveal infinitude: The mountain with its singular bright shade Like the blue shine on freshly frozen snow, The after-light upon ice-burdened pines; Odor of basswood on a mountain-slope, A scent beloved of bees; Silence of water above a sunken tree : The pure serene of memory in one man, &amp;ndash; A ripple widening from a single stone Winding around the waters of the world.
T. Roethke, The Far Field</description></item><item><title>Working With Me - A Manual For Transparent Collaboration</title><link>https://jgoldfar.github.io/blog/2021/05/21/working-with-me/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 May 2021 09:33:47 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jgoldfar.github.io/blog/2021/05/21/working-with-me/</guid><description>Working With Jonathan Goldfarb Since I have felt a dedication to authenticity and transparency my entire professional career, I am a bit embarrassed that I didn&amp;rsquo;t come up with the concept of a &amp;ldquo;user manual&amp;rdquo; for myself. Who hasn&amp;rsquo;t avoided going to an office-mate or boss because they weren&amp;rsquo;t sure how productive the conversation would be? Those kinds of missed opportunities can so easily be avoided with open communication in an organization.</description></item><item><title>Simple Python Hash Table</title><link>https://jgoldfar.github.io/blog/2021/04/22/python-hashtable/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Apr 2021 09:00:47 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jgoldfar.github.io/blog/2021/04/22/python-hashtable/</guid><description>&lt;p>The &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hash_table">hash table&lt;/a> or hash map is one of the fundamental data structures in computing.
It is an abstraction that allows a programming language user to think about
their problem at a level that is closer to the specifications developed for
business processes, instead of considering how the associated data is stored.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What? Context</title><link>https://jgoldfar.github.io/blog/2021/03/27/about/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Mar 2021 09:00:47 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jgoldfar.github.io/blog/2021/03/27/about/</guid><description>If you&amp;rsquo;re reading this post, you might be looking for some context around the blog and this section on the site. This blog is a place to discuss things learned and ask questions, and the posts that I write are often just starting points for dialogue online or offline.
One of my goals as a communicator is to facilitate simple, clear, and effective dialogue involving complex ideas. Oftentimes, I can&amp;rsquo;t achieve that goal in a blog post - clarity can require interaction between the reader, the subject, and the environment.</description></item><item><title>Why Noether Rudin?</title><link>https://jgoldfar.github.io/blog/2020/06/22/why-noether-rudin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2020 10:26:50 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jgoldfar.github.io/blog/2020/06/22/why-noether-rudin/</guid><description>&lt;p>Originally published on blog.noetherrudin.com, then on blog.getdolr.com, this piece summarized my support for an effort to get more money for people&amp;rsquo;s student loans.
I still love developing, sharing, and applying knowledge in service of good causes.
If you would like to find out more, &lt;a href="https://jgoldfar.github.io/contact">contact me!&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>