<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>web log on Jonathan Goldfarb</title><link>https://jgoldfar.github.io/blog/</link><description>Recent content in web log on Jonathan Goldfarb</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 23:18:17 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jgoldfar.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Feedback welcome (and how)!</title><link>https://jgoldfar.github.io/blog/2024/02/07/20240207-feedback-welcome/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 15:00:47 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jgoldfar.github.io/blog/2024/02/07/20240207-feedback-welcome/</guid><description>Folks who read the posts on this blog may notice that the comment form, previously integrated via Disqus, has been removed.
For a blog such as this one, the moderation overhead far outweighed the value that those forms provided.
While I am more interested than ever in your feedback, the comment form hasn&amp;rsquo;t been the best place for good feedback.
Email continues to be the best way to reach out; if you have a topic suggestion, a question, or just want to say &amp;ldquo;hey&amp;rdquo;, I&amp;rsquo;m always available at jgoldfar@gmail.</description></item><item><title>Does DRY mean one thing?</title><link>https://jgoldfar.github.io/blog/2024/01/29/20240129-dont-repeat-yourself/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2024 15:00:47 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jgoldfar.github.io/blog/2024/01/29/20240129-dont-repeat-yourself/</guid><description>A few weeks ago, I posted a poll on LinkedIn asking the question &amp;ldquo;What does DRY really mean?&amp;rdquo;
The options folks could choose from were
a) Don&amp;rsquo;t Repeat Yourself b) Do Repeat Yourself c) Don&amp;rsquo;t Remember Yesterday d) Something else
Aside from the bit of fun that a poll on a social media network can be — they&amp;rsquo;re engagement tools, not standardized tests after all — the reason I posed the question was to see if anyone would choose anything other than the oft-shared software development idiom in option a.</description></item><item><title>Find me in 2024</title><link>https://jgoldfar.github.io/blog/2023/12/28/20231229-outreach/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2023 15:00:47 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jgoldfar.github.io/blog/2023/12/28/20231229-outreach/</guid><description>Visitors to this blog may notice that I haven&amp;rsquo;t published much recently here; my recent content strategy has emphasized social media platforms and to a larger extent my internal stakeholders.
Follow the links in the top bar to see what I mean. The real value for me is in direct messages, which you won&amp;rsquo;t see, but if you reach out I&amp;rsquo;ll get back to you.
I am somewhat active on LinkedIn and have great engagement with folks in the industry.</description></item><item><title>Doing New Things</title><link>https://jgoldfar.github.io/blog/2022/01/04/0917-too-many-things/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2022 17:00:47 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jgoldfar.github.io/blog/2022/01/04/0917-too-many-things/</guid><description>Complete the form below to sign up for updates - new things are in the works every day.
I&amp;rsquo;ll be sharing what I&amp;rsquo;m doing, and will reach out to you personally if you indicate a specific interest.
Loading…</description></item><item><title>IAMA Faculty @ A Private Engineering College</title><link>https://jgoldfar.github.io/blog/2021/09/17/0103-ama-engineering-college/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Sep 2021 09:00:47 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jgoldfar.github.io/blog/2021/09/17/0103-ama-engineering-college/</guid><description>As an educator with 5 years as a full-time faculty member at an engineering college, I have had the pleasure of working with incredibly intelligent people of all levels of seniority. It is a great privilege to have the opportunity to share my knowledge, work with students, and observe the learning process. Observing - carefully and compassionately noticing what a student is doing - is one of the most powerful modalities for education.</description></item><item><title>How To Make Sense of the NodeJS Event Loop</title><link>https://jgoldfar.github.io/blog/2021/06/12/0501-how-to-make-sense-of-nodejs-event-loop/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2021 09:00:47 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jgoldfar.github.io/blog/2021/06/12/0501-how-to-make-sense-of-nodejs-event-loop/</guid><description>When you&amp;rsquo;re writing JavaScript code for NodeJS, you don&amp;rsquo;t often need to think about how your code will be executed. You may be thinking about the models you are working with, how data moves through your application, or what guarantees you need to be able to provide to meet your acceptance criteria - or you may have another framework in mind.
One of the great things about JavaScript on the Node runtime as a developer is that you get to write code at a high level and have your code execute efficiently on hardware.</description></item><item><title>Python + Flask CRUD Application Scaffold</title><link>https://jgoldfar.github.io/blog/2021/06/05/0605-python-flask-crud-application/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jun 2021 09:00:47 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jgoldfar.github.io/blog/2021/06/05/0605-python-flask-crud-application/</guid><description>I have found it useful to prepare boilerplate code for spinning up things like a new application; in this article, I&amp;rsquo;ll share some code for prototyping an application that can create, retrieve, update, and delete records from a database using Flask. This walkthrough will assume familiarity with the command line, and that a Python 3 interpreter is available.
For developers with experience with Django, Flask is familiar but with a smaller footprint, and leaves more up to the application architect when it comes to implementation details like form validation and data persistence.</description></item><item><title>All Finite Things Reveal Infinitude</title><link>https://jgoldfar.github.io/blog/2021/05/31/0102-finite-things-reveal-infinitude/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 May 2021 10:26:50 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jgoldfar.github.io/blog/2021/05/31/0102-finite-things-reveal-infinitude/</guid><description>All finite things reveal infinitude: The mountain with its singular bright shade Like the blue shine on freshly frozen snow, The after-light upon ice-burdened pines; Odor of basswood on a mountain-slope, A scent beloved of bees; Silence of water above a sunken tree : The pure serene of memory in one man, &amp;ndash; A ripple widening from a single stone Winding around the waters of the world.
T. Roethke, The Far Field</description></item><item><title>Working With Me - A Manual For Transparent Collaboration</title><link>https://jgoldfar.github.io/blog/2021/05/21/0521-working-with-me/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 May 2021 09:33:47 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jgoldfar.github.io/blog/2021/05/21/0521-working-with-me/</guid><description>Working With Me, Jonathan Goldfarb Dedication to authenticity and transparency is central to my work. In my continuous search for better ways to facilitate open and effective communication, I came across the concept of a personal &amp;ldquo;user manual&amp;rdquo;, a living document that encapsulates how I work with others. I can&amp;rsquo;t count the number of times a colleague has told me they avoided a conversation with an office-mate or colleague because they weren&amp;rsquo;t sure how productive the conversation would be.</description></item><item><title>Simple Python Hash Table</title><link>https://jgoldfar.github.io/blog/2021/04/22/0422-python-hashtable/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Apr 2021 09:00:47 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jgoldfar.github.io/blog/2021/04/22/0422-python-hashtable/</guid><description>&lt;p>The &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hash_table">hash table&lt;/a> or hash map is one of the fundamental data structures in computing.
It is an abstraction that allows a programming language user to think about
their problem at a level that is closer to the specifications developed for
business processes, instead of considering how the associated data is stored.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What is this? Some context for this weblog</title><link>https://jgoldfar.github.io/blog/2021/03/27/0101-about/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Mar 2021 09:00:47 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jgoldfar.github.io/blog/2021/03/27/0101-about/</guid><description>If you&amp;rsquo;re here reading this post, you might be looking for context this section on my personal site. What is a blog, and what is this blog?
To save you some time, I&amp;rsquo;ll just tell you what you won&amp;rsquo;t find: you won&amp;rsquo;t always find &amp;ldquo;quality&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;strong opinions weakly held&amp;rdquo;, or &amp;ldquo;an identifiable theme&amp;rdquo;.
I may repeat myself or I may contradict myself.
I may post original content, excerpt and critique on someone else&amp;rsquo;s work, or respond to your feedback.</description></item><item><title>Why Student Loan Repayment?</title><link>https://jgoldfar.github.io/blog/2020/06/22/0622-why-noether-rudin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2020 10:26:50 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jgoldfar.github.io/blog/2020/06/22/0622-why-noether-rudin/</guid><description>&lt;p>Originally published at blog.noetherrudin.com, then at blog.getdolr.com, this piece summarized my reason for co-founding a student loan repayment company.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I still love developing, sharing, and applying knowledge in service of good causes; if you have an vision for a new way to achieve a positive goal, &lt;a href="https://jgoldfar.github.io/contact">contact me!&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>